James Isbell

Greater Seattle Area



jisbell01@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/james-isbell

Summary

I excel at breaking down concepts or ideas from others and rapidly producing functional prototypes in whatever language or software is asked for. I've built game systems in Unreal Engine 4 in both C++ and Blueprint, Unity's C#, the Java Development Kit, and even UDK's UnrealScript.

I've also become skilled at cross-disciplinary communication; partially from my time at Mish Mash Machine and partially from independently learning the tools the other disciplines use. I've learned 3D modeling and animation with Maya, 2D art with Photoshop, and level design with the Unreal Editor, to name a few.

I have a personal interest in AI development, in both the NPCs that players directly interact with and the behind-the-scenes AI storytellers that work to create engaging experiences for players.

If you need a code example, I can provide a link to my github repositories.

Experience

Game Tester

C2S Technologies, Inc.

Oct 2021 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Lead Programmer

Paradigm Shift Entertainment

Sep 2015 - Jun 2018 (2 years 10 months)

Prototyped games built in Unreal Engine 4 using both blueprint and C++

Lead Programmer

MISH MASH MACHINE LLC

Feb 2014 - Jul 2015 (1 year 6 months)

- I managed a small team of programmers to quickly and efficiently build out the C# code base for the touchscreen game "Raising Hell" in the Unity3D engine.
- I worked with the creative team to rapidly develop prototypes of their ideas for play-testing by the group
- I worked with the artists to create an efficient pipeline for them to create and add assets into the game
- I helped create/manage/maintain the company's GitHub repositories for our projects
- At conventions, I managed the technical needs of the booth while also taking and organizing feedback from players for later discussion by the team.

Accomplishments:

Released "Raising Hell" for iOS, Windows, and Android touchscreen-enabled devices.

Showcased "Raising Hell" at the Microsoft-sponsored North Texas Indie Developers booths at PAX South

Showcased "Raising Hell" at the Big Design Conference

Education



Associate's degree, Computer Science I paused the degree when I got hired.

Skills

Unreal Engine 4 • C++ • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Game Design • Video Games • Game Development • C# • Unity3D • Java • JavaScript